#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

## EMMA WHEAT

BA Hons • ACC • CPCC

People Development | Executive & Leadership Coaching

emma.wheat@gmail.com +971 50 728 1969 mobile +9714 326 8839 ph

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

## People Development, Coaching Professional

Offering 20+ years' experience in People Development/Education, Coaching and Senior Management/Corporate positions; since 2007 training and coaching with clients such as Volkswagen, Astra Zenea, Glaxo Smithkline and Dubai Transport.; offering unique cross cultural experience from 16 years spent in the Middle East.

"Building foundations for inspired corporate performance."

CAREER HISTORY

Corporate Trainer, Facilitator, Leadership Coach (Dubai) 2006 - present

Facilitating workshops, conducting training, leading teams of coaches, creating 'high impact' coaching to achieve immediate results in the areas of Career Transition Management, Leadership and Work-Life Balance;

Additionally leading the provision of Hogan Personality Testing, Performance Prediction and other diagnostic reporting services.

Achievements included being engaged by clients such as Dubai Government organisations; Capgemini University, Paris; Dubai Transport; Volkswagen; Glaxo Smithkline; Newell Rubbermaid and Astra Zeneca;

Freelance Appointments 1) Faculty Member and Trainer, Facilitator for the Coaches Training Institute; 2) Authorised Facilitator at Capgemini University,

3) International Team Leader, Global Services, Ricklin-Echikson Associates, US; and Completing an Executive Coaching programme at a top UAE bank.

## Corporate Ambassador | Executive Coach

Informa Group – IIR Middle East (Dubai)

2006 - 2007

Serving as the key link between IIR (a corporate training and people development consultancy) and clients throughout the Gulf Region, promoting the IIR business development and its programmes;

Driving the creation and implementation of innovative learning programmes, and development practices and procedures, liaising with client' Senior Managers; And serving as an Executive Coach to internal team members at IIR.

Note - spend 2005/6 travelling through South Africa, Europe, Thailand, South America and the UK; wrote a book and achieved other personal goals.]

## **International Sales Manager**

Cityscape Exhibition - IIR Middle East (Dubai)

2003 - 2005

Launching and managing Cityscape Exhibition and Awards, Dubai World Trade Centre – spearheading the introduction of new commercial exhibitions to Dubai Achievements included managing the Top 5 key accounts for large scale events with >USD1m budgets; and successfully driving growth and expansion, developing new international business to Cityscape by 50% in 2004.continues on p 2

"Sparking inspired performances, superior leadership and outstanding achievement on the part of individuals and teams"

Corporate Client, Dubai

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

Internationally experienced People Development Coach, Facilitator and Educator

> Specialist fields include Leadership, Team and Individual Performance; Career Transition and Cultural Diversity

Clients included VW, Astra Zeneca & Glaxo Smithkline

Certified Coach (ACC), ICF

Certified Professional Coactive Coach, CTI

## **TESTIMONIALS**

"Emma Wheat is a worldclass coach with flair, courage and compelling beauty who can edge any individual or team beyond their comfort zone into fulfillment and action."

## -Celeste Schenck, President AUP, Paris

"...an inspiring coach trainer you helped me transition to a leadership role; you helped me to trust my abilities and challenge my doubts. I learned so much. There are so many things I will keep coming back to for many years".

> Max Herner, Manager, Capgemini, Norway

CAREER HISTORY: SUMMARY OF PREVIOUS POSITIONS

## Assistant Trade & Investments Officer

British Embassy (Dubai)

2001 - 2003

Organising and marketing high profile events, bringing new companies to the Dubai market and building links and partnerships to develop trade relations.

Achievements included building valuable relationships with leading UAE women participating in the "Women in Business" initiative; and hosting and managing events and functions for local VIPs and members of the UK Royal Family.

## Assessment Coordinator | Senior Management Team

Jebel Ali School (Dubai)

1997 - 2000

Managing Quality Assurance for the school, ensuring Teachers were assessed, mentored and developed in order to delivery world-class education;

Conducting a training needs analysis and designing and implementing corresponding development programmes.

CAREER HISTORY: SUMMARY OF PREVIOUS POSITIONS

**Teacher | Management Team Member**, Wesgreen International School (Sharjah, UAE), 1996 – 1997. Teaching pupils and leading the appraising and training of staff.

**Assessment Coordinator** | **Management Team Member**, Woodford Junior School (UK), 1992 – 1996. Planning, coordinating and implementing curriculum across "Key Stages" I and II; and developing staff to support the new curriculum.

Probationary Teacher, Hatchford Primary School (UK), 1991 - 1992.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Authorised Facilitator: Team Diagnostic Assessment

Certified Assessor: Hogan Assessments

Associate Certified Coach (ACC), International Coaching Federation (ICF)

Trainer, Facilitator & Faculty Member, Coaches Training Institute

Organisational Relationship Systems Coach (ORSC)

Certified Customer Service Manager, 2006

## **EDUCATION**

Hogan Assessment, 2009

Team Diagnostic Assessment, 2008 (Stockholm)

Leadership Programme, Coaches Training Institute, 2008 - 2009 (Spain)

Advanced Coaches Certification Course, Coaches Training Institute, 2007

Organisational Systems Relationship Coaching, 2007

Strategic Skills Forum for Senior Managers, 2006

Teaching English as a Foreign Language (TEFL) Certification, UK 1996

Bachelor of Arts Hons Degree, Warwick University (UK), 1991

References and Certificates Available on Request.

### **TESTIMONIALS**

"Emma makes participants feel seen. She creates impact, inspires desire for change ..."

"What a strong, passionate and authoritative presence she is in front of a group"

-Carola Vermeulen, Senior Trainer, Capgemini University, Paris

"[Emma] is compassionate and exacting, insightful and genuinely committed to the people she coaches"

> - Participant, Emerging Leadership Programme

### ADVANCED SKILLS

## Training Development – from needs analysis to implementation

## Business Development – Increasing and developing new international clients

## Motivating and Training – improving team performance through appraisals, assessment and follow-up

## Inter-Personal Skills – building relationships at all corporate levels

**Training** – injecting passion, enthusiasm, focus and professional excellence

# Mentoring and Coaching – assisting individuals and teams to unlock superior performance and achievement